RIDWAN OLAWUMI ADEAGBO

12 Road 18, Agaloke Estate, Apata, Ibadan P: 08078457639, 07039268946 | adeagboridwan@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ridwanolawumiadeagbo

Sales Representative | Customer Service | Bilingual (French and English)

SUMMARY

Bilingual (French and English) Business Development professional who is effective in building and maintaining loyal customer base to maintain consistent revenue stream.

Customer-oriented, strategic-thinking sales professional with 6 years of experience in building relationships, cultivating partnerships, retaining top accounts and growing profit channels

SKILLS

Communication skill | Analytical skill | Teamwork | Flexible and Reliable Relationship selling | Customer needs assessment | Problem solving Sales development | Leadership | Client account management Network expansion | Product and service knowledge

EXPERIENCE

ROGBARID VENTURES, ABEOKUTA Sales Representative

February 2019 – Present

- Generated over #30MM revenue by Implementing consultative sales techniques, thereby exceeding sales target by 2.5%
- Expanded network by 12% by attending industry events, identifying and pursuing Leads and establishing rapport with new clients
- Successfully negotiated 25 Local Purchase Orders worth about #33MM from ELALAN Construction Company Limited, Jordan Brookes Estate Limited, Akin Asphalt Solutions and Business Contracting Limited.
- Creatively communicated product quality and market comparisons through implementation of 2 professional sales presentations
- Cultivated a 17% increase in client relationship by asking appropriate questions, identifying needs and providing insightful information regarding product

GUARANTY TRUST BANK PLC, IBARA ABEOKUTA Relationship Officer November 2017 – February 2019

- Achieved 90% of the year's acquisition target by attracting about 9,500 new customers in 2018
- Increased account transactions by 32% by delivering products to customers daily
- Enhanced loyalty and retention of about 10,000 customers by fostering relationship with them

- Increased portfolio by #522MM through client-focused approach to strategic account management
- Grew account compliance rate by 55% by processing Enhanced Due Diligence
- Broadened the knowledge of client and team members by addressing an average of 25 inquiries daily from them

GUARANTY TRUST BANK PLC, ASERO ABEOKUTA Teller/ Customer Service

May 2014 - November 2017

- Met 78% of sales goal by promoting the bank's product and service in every transaction
- Ensured that 4 new employees and 6 interns delivered above 80% performance satisfaction after I had trained and supervised them
- Skyrocketed the branch's rating to 2nd position from 7th position in region by encouraging the use of e-channels and minimizing and correcting errors
- Reduced complaint calls by 31% through answering questions daily and addressing concerns
- Delivered prompt, accurate and excellent customer service

EDUCATION

KWARA STATE POLYTECHNIC, ILORIN, NIGERIA

 Higher National Diploma, Statistics; cumulative GPA of 3.39/4.0 November 2011

 Ordinary National Diploma, Statistics; cumulative GPA of 3.36/4.0 June 2008

ADDITIONAL

Languages: Fluent in English, Yoruba; Intermediate-advanced Proficiency in French

Certifications & Training: Sales Prospecting and Leads Generation

Alison Online Academy | Credential ID - 1238-15794379 April 2020

Diploma in Customer Service

Alison Online Academy | Credential ID - 1540-15794379 April 2020

Diploma in French Language Studies

Alison Online Academy | Credential ID – 1883-15794379 April 2020

International Credential Evaluation Service

British Columbia Institute of Technology - A01179322 June 2019

• Information Technology, Community Development

Service Group, National Youth Service Corps, Calabar, Nigeria Oct 2012

Data Analytics (In view) – Alison online academy

Interests: Travelling, Meeting people, Selling